<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<blog>
    <post slug="cache-data-in-symfony2">
        <title>Cache Data in Symfony2</title>
        <resume>Use Doctrine library to cache data in Symfony2</resume>
        <content>
            <![CDATA[
            <div class="post">
                <p>Doctrine provides a Cache Layer. A very good one, indeed. So if you need to cache data use Doctrine/Commons.</p>

                <p>This Cache Layer abstracts the caching functionality and provides already various different backends for your caching data.</p>

                <p>These are already build-in in the master version:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>APC</li>
                    <li>Array</li>
                    <li>Filesystem</li>
                    <li>Memcache</li>
                    <li>PhpFile</li>
                    <li>Redis</li>
                    <li>WinCache</li>
                    <li>Xcache</li>
                    <li>ZendData</li>
                </ul>

                <p>You could even create your own on top of the CacheProvider class and the Cache interface.</p>

                <p>In your Symfony2 project simply register your cache service of choice and your ready to go.</p>
                <p>In your config.yml or services.yml add:</p>

<pre class="prettyprint" lang="yml">
cache:
    class: Doctrine\Common\Cache\PhpFileCache
    arguments: [%kernel.cache_dir%]
</pre>

                <p>And in your controller you can call the service and save and load data from the cache.</p>

<pre class="prettyprint">
$cache = $this->get('cache');
$cache->setNamespace('mynamespace.cache');

if (false === ($cached_data = $cache->fetch($cache_key)))
{
    $cached_data = $SOMEAPI->getData($params);
    $cache->save($cache_key, $cached_data, 3600);//TTL 1h
}
</pre>

                <p>As you can see you can set a namespace for your cache data, so that you can easy use it for different scenarions in the same app.</p>
                <p>Further you can set a time-to-live (TTL) in seconds as third parameter of the save method.</p>

                <p>So after all symfony2 has a caching mechanism for data, its just a little hidden in the Doctrine/Commons dependency.</p>

                <small><a href="http://nerdpress.org/2012/07/10/caching-data-in-symfony2/" target="_blank">Original source</a></small>
            </div>
            ]]>
        </content>
        <image></image>
        <date>23 July, 2012</date>
        <category>tutorial</category>
        <tags>Symfony2, Doctrine, Cache</tags>
    </post>
    <post slug="mysql-and-phpmyadmin-on-fedora-16">
        <title>MySQL and phpMyAdmin on Fedora 16</title>
        <resume>How to setup MySQL and phpMyAdmin on Fedora 16</resume>
        <content>
            <![CDATA[
            <div class="post">
                <p>For my surprise, after installing MySQL server, there was no service mysqld in /etc/init.d, so I could not start mysql server with the command /etc/init.d/mysqld start</p>

                <h3>Installating MySQL</h3>
                <div class="prettyprint">
                    # yum install mysql-server
                </div>

                <p>So it seems that now, to start a service we must run the command systemctl.</p>

                <div class="prettyprint">
                    # systemctl start mysqld.service
                </div>

                <p>In case you want to enable the mysql when you start your computer:</p>

                <div class="prettyprint">
                    # systemctl enable mysqld.service
                </div>

                <p>Another thing that hit me by surprise is that phpMyAdmin doesn’t work out of the box, you need to configure some options.</p>
                <p>Edit the files /etc/httpd/conf.d/phpMyAdmin.conf and /etc/phpMyAdmin/config.inc.php (main one).</p>
                <p>In my case, I set a random string to the blowfish_secret option, changed auth_type to cookie instead of the default http, and changed to TRUE the option to allow no password (AllowNoPassword).</p>
                <p>After a restart of the apache server (# systemctl restart httpd.service), I was ready to go.</p>
            </div>
            ]]>
        </content>
        <image></image>
        <date>11 November, 2012</date>
        <category>tutorial</category>
        <tags>MySQL, Fedora, phpMyAdmin</tags>
    </post>
    <post slug="avoid-password-prompt-on-the-command-line">
        <title>Avoid password prompt on the command line</title>
        <resume>Configure ssh to login automatically on a remote server</resume>
        <content>
            <![CDATA[
            <div class="post">
                <p>In case you often connect to remote server and get bored of typing the password all the time, there is a solution.</p>

                <p>Create a public key, running the command</p>

                <div class="prettyprint">
                $ ssh-keygen -t rsa
                </div>

                <p>A file ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub will be created with your public key.</p>

                <p><strong>Now, publish the key to the server</strong></p>

                <div class="prettyprint">
                cat ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub | ssh USER@DOMAIN.COM "cat >> .ssh/authorized_keys"
                </div>

                <p>And this will be the last time you will be asked for the password. Test if everything went as expect executing</p>

                <div class="prettyprint">
                ssh USER@DOMAIN.COM
                </div>

                <p>You should login immediately, without being asked for the password.</p>
            </div>
            ]]>
        </content>
        <image></image>
        <date>25 April, 2012</date>
        <category>tutorial</category>
        <tags>SSH, Bash</tags>
    </post>
    <post slug="google-chrome-fonts-fix">
        <title>Google Chrome fonts fix</title>
        <resume>Fix the renderization of fonts on Google Chrome</resume>
        <content>
            <![CDATA[
            <div class="post">
                <p>Google Chrome version 7.0.517.44 in my Fedora 13 box renders fonts in a funny way even after the instalation of the windows fonts.</p>
                <p>Fixed the problem creating the file ~/.fonts.conf with the following xml code:</p>

<pre class="prettyprint">
&lt;match target="font"&gt;
    &lt;edit name="autohint" mode="assign"&gt;
        &lt;bool&gt;true&lt;/bool&gt;
    &lt;/edit&gt;
    &lt;edit name="hinting" mode="assign"&gt;
        &lt;bool>true&lt;/bool&gt;
    &lt;/edit&gt;
    &lt;edit mode="assign" name="hintstyle"&gt;
        &lt;const&gt;hintslight&lt;/const&gt;
    &lt;/edit&gt;
&lt;/match&gt;
</pre>
            </div>
            ]]>
        </content>
        <image></image>
        <date>22 April, 2012</date>
        <category>fix</category>
        <tags>Fonts, Google Chrome, Fedora</tags>
    </post>
</blog>
